in 1986 Ben and Jerry's headquarters
received a postcard from Jane Williamson
a die-hard ice cream fan asking for
cherry flavored cream based on Grateful
Dead member Jerry Garcia both Ben and
Jerry loved the idea Ben led the flavor
tasting process and created what is to
this day one of the most popular and
longest served flavors of all time the
only issue is one pint has over a
thousand calories and I can eat a pint
in 10 minutes in today's video I will
divulge all the secrets for an authentic
Cherry Garcia but with half the calories
let's
get into it originally Cherry Garcia had
a vanilla base but in recent years they
changed it to a cherry base so we'll
grab a high sided container and into it
add 20 grams of cherry juice this isn't
just any cherry juice but the juice from
bing cherries since its Inception Ben
and Jerry have used bing cherries as
noted by the book they wrote way back in
1987. luckily Whole Foods sells bing
cherries sitting in the juices sweet
nectar you can also get them on Amazon
which I will link in the description
below in the testing process I also
tried juicing and straining my own
cherries but Rainer cherries just didn't
have the same taste as the bing cherries
and I couldn't find fresh bing cherries
anywhere however this is a viable option
if you want something cheaper and more
readily available with our Cherry
situation taken care of we will then add
380 grams 2 percent high protein milk 2
egg yolks and 4 grams vanilla extract in
the book they act actually call for two
whole eggs but since we are subbing out
heavy cream for milk I would rather not
add any additional water that will make
the ice cream icier so I will separate
the egg white from the yolk and only add
the yolks to the mixture if you don't
want to use egg yolks for whatever
reason you can sub in 30 grams of two
percent milk but you will be drastically
reducing overall flavor and mouth feel
don't say I didn't warn you now grab a
measuring cup and into it add 16 grams
of a vanilla whey casein blend protein
powder preferably from PE science whey
alone may work here but I have never
tried it before just make sure the
vanilla tastes good or else you will
want to smack me with the ice cream
because it wasn't what you thought it
would be next up we have 40 grams of
urethritol or swerve I tried testing
sucralose and swerve in the ice cream
for more sweetness and a cheaper price
but it didn't work out like I wanted it
to even after multiple taste tests
if
I'm guessing this one's the swerve since
this is the one that was super smooth
all swerve makes a smoother ice cream
I'm gonna go with the swerve all day we
will finish the dry ingredients off with
a half gram of salt and 0.8 grams of
xanthan gum
don't skip the xanthan gum it makes ice
cream taste like ice cream when it is
swirling around in your mouth
trust me take a spoon or fork and mix
these ingredients up thoroughly now
we'll take our wet ingredients and an
immersion blender and start mixing
slowly add in the dry ingredients over a
30 second period and continue to blend
for 90 additional seconds there are also
120 additional recipes in my cookbook
that have been helping countless people
lose weight and keep it off while
enjoying each and every meal this
includes my protein potato bun recipe
that won't be on YouTube for weeks but
is already in the cookbook for you to
enjoy get my cookbook receive new
recipes before anyone else and start
losing weight today now we'll add our
melted ice cream into a pint label it
not to get confused with our other
creams and add it to the freezer 24
hours later nature is calling to eat
some cream but before we eat we need to
get our mixins ready the thing I have
always loved about Ben Jerry's is that
they do not skimp on the mix-ins and you
get some in every Spoonful so with that
in mind mind let's get to work as we
discussed earlier we need some bing
cherries luckily we have a jar of them
ready to go we do need to remove a lot
of the juice though or it will not only
melt the ice cream but make the ice
cream crystallize while it is spinning
to avoid that I grab a triple layer of
paper towels get five cherries out of
the jar take the stems off open each one
up and press them into the towel the
amount of juice that soaks in the towel
would make our ice cream into a watery
milkshake so make sure not to skip this
step for a cheaper option you can also
deseed your own Rainer cherries open
them up and add 100 grams to a small
bowl then add 10 grams of sugar over the
top and mix around with the spoon they
will be ready in 30 minutes and then
follow the same procedure with the paper
towel I did this for the first 10 or so
attempts and they were good but they
just didn't have that same flavor as a
bing Cherry then comes the chocolate in
the recipe book Ben and Jerry call for
Hershey's dark chocolate chocolate but
they also say that using the highest
quality ingredients is the most
important for the best ice cream so I
did what I do best and bought a bunch of
chocolate tried them all and took down
cream after cream to see which tasted
best I don't even like dark
chocolate ironically the best flavor
when paired with the ice cream was the
Hershey's so we will take 15 grams of
chocolate and chop it into 1 8 inch
chunks similar to what you would find in
today's Cherry Garcia all that is left
to do is wash the outside of the Pint
under hot water for one minute load it
into the creamy and run it on the sorbet
setting
yes the sorbet setting the difference
between these settings is only a change
in the amount of seconds the blade goes
down and up and the speed of the blade
while going down and up that is why it
is crucial to test different settings
out for different cream recipes and for
the absolutely thickest cream possible
which we need for a Ben and Jerry style
ice cream is the sorbet setting once
spun we are ready to load our mixins in
take a knife and pull out a nice gaping
hole in the middle fill it up with a
layer of chocolate followed by a layer
of cherries and repeat until all mix-ins
are added add the ice cream on the knife
back into the cream and use the mix-in
setting to finish the best copycat
creamy ice cream on all of the internet
if you want to venture into cream Heaven
add a couple of Scoops to a waffle cone
and enjoy the fruits of your labor this
cream packs pure Cherry Garcia flavor
without having you pack on the pounds
the only issue is if you are in a larger
calorie deficit it you might need ice
cream with even lower calories that is
why I made pints of ice cream that are
only 150 calories per pint which you
could find in this video here these will
help you lose weight no matter how steep
the calorie deficit and I can't wait to
cream with you there that was so damn
good just pipe the out of that cone
until next time deuces